questions = {
    "easy": [
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Moomin family's home in the Moomin books?",
            "options": ["Moominland", "Moomin House", "Moomin Valley", "Moomin Cottage"],
            "answer": "Moomin House"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Finnish word for 'beer'?",
            "options": ["Vesi", "Olut", "Kala", "Liha"],
            "answer": "Olut"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Finnish word for 'hello'?",
            "options": ["Moi", "Hei", "Terve", "Kiitos"],
            "answer": "Hei"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these cities is not in Finland?",
            "options": ["Turku", "Tampere", "Gothenburg", "Oulu"],
            "answer": "Gothenburg"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these cities is in Finland?",
            "options": ["Turku", "Turek", "Turkey", "Pabianice"],
            "answer": "Turku"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the capital of Finland?",
            "options": ["Helsinki", "Stockholm", "Oslo", "Copenhagen"],
            "answer": "Helsinki"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the currency of Finland?",
            "options": ["Euro", "Crown", "Mark", "Ruble"],
            "answer": "Euro"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the official language of Finland?",
            "options": ["Finnish", "Swedish", "English", "Russian"],
            "answer": "Finnish"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous Finnish mobile phone manufacturer?",
            "options": ["Nokia", "Ericsson", "Motorola", "Samsung"],
            "answer": "Nokia"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish Prime Minister?",
            "options": ["Sanna Marin", "Juha Sipilä", "Alexander Stubb", "Jyrki Katainen"],
            "answer": "Sanna Marin"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish national epic poem?",
            "options": ["Kalevala", "Eddas", "Nibelungenlied", "Beowulf"],
            "answer": "Kalevala"
        }
    ],
    "medium": [
        {
          "question": "Which region of Finland has the highest concentration of Swedish-speakers?",
          "options": ["Helsinki", "Lapland", "Åland Islands", "Tampere"],
          "answer": "Åland Islands"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the status of Swedish in Finland?",
          "options": [
            "It is the only official language of the country.",
            "It is not recognized as an official language of the country.",
            "It is one of the two official languages of the country, along with Finnish.",
            "It is a minority language that is not taught in schools."
          ],
          "answer": "It is one of the two official languages of the country, along with Finnish."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what year did the Winter War begin?",
          "options": ["1939", "1940", "1941", "1942"],
          "answer": "1939"
        },
        {
          "question": "Who was the famous Finnish sniper who fought during the Winter War and was credited with 505 confirmed kills?",
          "options": ["Simo Häyhä","Matti Aho","Reino Lehväslaiho","Vilho Rättö"],
          "answer": "Simo Häyhä"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish Santa Claus?",
            "options": ["Joulupukki", "Joulupukkiainen", "Joulupukkikuu", "Joulupukkiviikko"],
            "answer": "Joulupukki"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish ski jumper who won four consecutive Olympic gold medals?",
            "options": ["Simo Häyhä", "Paavo Nurmi", "Matti Nykänen", "Hannu Manninen"],
            "answer": "Matti Nykänen"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish racing driver who won the Formula One World Championship in 1982?",
            "options": ["Keke Rosberg", "Mika Häkkinen", "Kimi Räikkönen", "Valtteri Bottas"],
            "answer": "Keke Rosberg"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish composer who wrote the music for the popular video game 'Angry Birds'?",
            "options": ["Jean Sibelius", "Einojuhani Rautavaara", "Kaija Saariaho", "Ari Pulkkinen"],
            "answer": "Ari Pulkkinen"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish architect who designed the Finlandia Hall in Helsinki?",
            "options": ["Eero Saarinen", "Alvar Aalto", "Juha Leiviskä", "Lars Sonck"],
            "answer": "Alvar Aalto"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish ice hockey player who won three Olympic medals and five World Championships?",
            "options": ["Teemu Selänne", "Jari Kurri", "Saku Koivu", "Esa Tikkanen"],
            "answer": "Teemu Selänne"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish band known for their hit song 'Hard Rock Hallelujah', which won the Eurovision Song Contest in 2006?",
            "options": ["Lordi", "HIM", "Nightwish", "The Rasmus"],
            "answer": "Lordi"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish author who wrote the popular Moomin books?",
            "options": ["Tove Jansson", "Mika Waltari", "Arto Paasilinna", "Sofi Oksanen"],
            "answer": "Tove Jansson"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Finnish composer wrote the symphonic poem 'Finlandia'?",
            "options": ["Jean Sibelius", "Einojuhani Rautavaara", "Kaija Saariaho", "Magnus Lindberg"],
            "answer": "Jean Sibelius"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is Viipuri?",
            "options": ["In Finland", "In Sweden", "In Norway", "In Russia"],
            "answer": "In Russia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following territories were annexed by the Soviet Union from Finland after the Winter War?",
            "options": ["Karelia and Petsamo", "Salla i Hanko", "Turku and Åland", "Oulu and Tampere"],
            "answer": "Karelia and Petsamo"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the traditional Finnish sauna practice where bathers flagellate themselves or each other with birch branches?",
            "options": ["Vihta", "Löyly", "Saunapalvi", "Kalsarikännit"],
            "answer": "Vihta"
        }
    ],
    "hard": [
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish painter who created the 'Under the North Star' trilogy?",
            "options": ["Eero Järnefelt", "Akseli Gallen-Kallela", "Helene Schjerfbeck", "Tove Jansson"],
            "answer": "Akseli Gallen-Kallela"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish film director who won the Best Foreign Language Film Oscar for 'The Man Without a Past'?",
            "options": ["Aki Kaurismäki", "Mika Kaurismäki", "Ella Lemhagen", "Antti Jokinen"],
            "answer": "Aki Kaurismäki"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Finnish scientist who won the 2008 Nobel Prize in Chemistry for his work on the green fluorescent protein?",
            "options": ["Pekka Pyykkö", "Ilkka Hanski", "Esko Kauppinen", "Osamu Shimomura"],
            "answer": "Osamu Shimomura"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which city, located in modern-day Russia, was known as Viipuri in Finnish and served as a major Finnish cultural center before being annexed by the Soviet Union?",
            "options": ["St. Petersburg", "Petsamo", "Petrozavodsk", "Vyborg"],
            "answer": "Vyborg"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was Lauri Törni?",
            "options": ["A Finnish soldier who fought in World War II and later in the Vietnam War", "A Finnish composer", "A Finnish Olympic athlete", "A Finnish scientist"],
            "answer": "A Finnish soldier who fought in World War II and later in the Vietnam War"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which area in northern Finland, known for its rich nickel deposits, was annexed by the Soviet Union after the Winter War?",
            "options": ["Petsamo", "Viipuri", "Karelia", "Tampere"],
            "answer": "Petsamo"
        }
    ]
}
